Soviet Union Unregistered Baptists Subject Files, Inclusive: 1948-2011, undated, Bulk: 1960-1989
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Soviet Union Unregistered Baptists Subject Files
Inclusive: 1948-2011, undated, Bulk: 1960-1989
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
29
The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
32 A4 Document Boxes
The Unregistered Baptist Subject Files contain a variety of materials on the history and persecution of unregistered Evangelical Christians - Baptists in the former Soviet Union.
Administrative Information
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria, and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports, and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
Beginning with the crackdown on religion instituted during the Khrushchev era, conflicting ideas arose as to how the Baptist Church in the Soviet Union should proceed. When the Soviet government began pressuring Baptists to restrict activities such as allowing children to participate in religious worship, altar calls at the ends of services, and baptisms of those under age 30, some churches withdrew their membership in the All-Union Council of Evangelical Christians Baptists (AUCECB) and thereby were no longer registered with the government and created the Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians-Baptists (CCECB). Churches and individuals within the group became known as Unregistered Baptists or Initsiativniki.
Shortly after its formation, the CCECB applied to the Soviet government for registration. The request was denied, and the decades of persecution ensued. Oppressive practices included imprisonment, desecration of buildings, restrictions on the education of children, physical violence, and prohibition of publication or use of religious literature.
Influential members were arrested and otherwise intimidated by the KGB and the Soviet government. These individuals included but were not limited to: Pastor Georgi Vins (Secretary Abroad of the CCECB), Pastor Nikolai Khrapov, Pastor Nikolai Baturin (General Secretary of the CCECB), Pastor Petr Rumachik (Vice-president of the CCECB), and Pastor Ivan Antonov (member of the CCECB). Their families were also KGB targets and were frequently arrested.
As a result, the Council of Prisoners’ Relatives was created. This female-led group collected details on Unregistered Baptists who had been imprisoned and circulated the information throughout the Soviet Union and abroad. Therefore, appeals to foreign countries, official documents, and other publications are contained in the collection. Lidia Vins, mother of Georgi Vins, served as the organization’s president.
Prohibition of printing religious texts and limited methods to spread the gospel plagued the Initsiativniki. Therefore, they created the Khristianin Press which created religious texts and writings from leaders to be circulated. Working with the printing was dangerous and led to many arrests.
Although Unregistered Baptists in the Soviet Union faced persecution and significant barriers to religious freedom, they managed to smuggle some of their work to the West. Their efforts allowed their story to be heard by notable people, as evidenced by discussions in the U.S. Congress and in several international religious forums. Key Initsiativniki supporters from abroad included Radio Liberty, Friedensstimme, Amnesty International, the World Council of Churches, and the Keston Institute.
Scope and Content
The Unregistered Baptist General Files contain a wide variety of materials, most commonly newspaper articles, cross references, newsletters, and periodical articles. However, there are also publication references, transcripts of interviews, handwritten letters, handwritten lists, bibliographies, confidential documents, U.S. Congressional records, bulletins, theses, research from Radio Liberty, photographs, and postcards. Much of the information spans the 1960’s to the late 1980’s. The files were created in order to preserve the history of the Unregistered Baptists in the Soviet Union and to collect their stories of persecution.
Materials related to notable individuals include: Georgi Vins, Mikhail Khorev, Veniamin Khorev, Maria Braun, Anna Chertkova, Ivan Moiseev, Aida Skripnikova, Lidia Vins, Peter Vins, Valen Ivanovitch Kuzin, Myrna Grant, Reverend Dick Rodgers, Irina Ratushinkskaya, Onufrii Antonovich Palamarchuk, Ivan Yakovlevich Pauls, Vanya Peters, Michael Bourdeaux, Janis Rozkalns, Petr Rumachik, Galina Ryitkova, Galina Vilchinskaya, K.I. Vladianu, Nikolai Ivanovich Vladykin, Boris Zdorovets, Ivan Biblenko, Nikolai Boiko, Joseph Bondarenko, Nikolai Deinega, Uliana/Stepan Germaniuk, Anatoly Khailo, Vladimir Khailo, Nikolai Khamara, Nikolai Khrapov, Rudolf Klassen, David Klassen, Nikolai Klassen, Vasilii Kozlov, Alexandra Kozorezova, Nikolai Kravchenko, Gennadii Kriuchkov, and Dimitri Miniakov.
Important events and topics include: the 1961 Schism, visits to the Soviet Union from the West, CCECB meetings, disruption of meetings, appeals to the Soviet government, evangelists working with children, the Khristianin printing press, house searches, confiscation of property, appeals to the West for help, attacks from secular media sources, emigration, Western organizations holding events to share information on persecuted Initsiativniki, believers at Barnaul, the release of prisoners, trials, the Council of Prisoners’ Relatives, and religious schooling.
Arrangement
The Keston Center received most of the Unregistered Baptists material in files organized by categories. This original filing system has been preserved. Items received by the Keston Center in no particular order are arranged thematically and chronologically.
The Unregistered Baptist Subject Files are arranged into two series: I. General and II. Samizdat.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 29.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Bourdeaux, Michael Allen, 1934-
Subjects (Organizations)
RFE/RL.; Sovet t︠s︡erkveiămp;& evangel)'skikh khristian-baptistov (Soviet Union)
Places
Soviet Union -- Church history.; Soviet Union -- Emigration and immigration.
Subjects
Baptism -- Baptists -- Soviet Union.; Baptist church buildings -- Soviet Union.; Baptists -- Clergy.; Baptists -- Soviet Union -- History.; Christianity -- Soviet Union.; Church and state -- Soviet Union -- History.; Demonstrations -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.; Freedom of religion -- Soviet Union.; Human rights -- Soviet Union.; Persecution -- Soviet Union -- History.; Propaganda, Soviet.; Protestant women -- Soviet Union.; Protestantism -- Soviet Union -- History.; Religion and state -- Soviet Union.; Religious education.; Underground Literature -- Soviet Union.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets.; Periodicals.; Photographs.; Publications.; Records (Documents); Registers (Lists).; Transcripts.
- General, 1948-2007, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Biography/Profile
  The Unregistered Baptist General Files document the history of the Unregistered Baptist Church in the Soviet Union, providing information on oppressive practices faced by the churches and individuals and the support they received transnationally. The series is in good condition.
  - Initsiativniki General (1 of 2), 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Initsiativniki General (2 of 2), 1969-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Initsiativniki History, 1961-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. General (A-M), 1969-2005, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. General (N-Z), 1964-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. Braun, Maria (Maria Golovina), 1966-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. Chertkova, Anna, 1987-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. Moiseev, Ivan (Vanya), 1972-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. Skripnikova, Aida, 1962-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. Vins Family (1 of 2), 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. Vins Family (2 of 2), 1979-1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptists. List of Names, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - List of Churches, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Churches, 1973-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Canon Law, 1965-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Finances, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Council of the Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (CCECB), 1961-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Council of the Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (CCECB). Congresses, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Council of the Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (CCECB). Members, 1961-1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Council of the Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (CCECB). Statements, Circulars, 1961-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church, State, and Law. General (1 of 2), 1965-1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church, State, and Law. General (2 of 2), 1973-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church-State Relations, 1948-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church-State Relations. Individual Cases, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church-State Relations. Legislation, 1976-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church-State Relations. Council for Religious Affairs, 1964-1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church-State Relations. Registration of Churches and Communities, 1970-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. General (1 of 4), 1964-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. General (2 of 4), 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. General (3 of 4), 1977-1979, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. General (4 of 4), 1980-1986, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Harassment, 1974-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Physical Assault, 1967-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Disruption of Meetings, 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Fines, 1976-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. Interrogations, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Trials (1 of 2), 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Trials (2 of 2), 1974-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (1 of 16), 1966-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (2 of 16), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (3 of 16), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (4 of 16), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (5 of 16), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (6 of 16), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (7 of 16), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (8 of 16), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (9 of 16), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (10 of 16), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (11 of 16), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Oppressive Practices: imprisonment (12 of 16), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (13 of 16), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (14 of 16), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (15 of 16), 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Imprisonment (16 of 16), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. State Expropriation, Desecration, or Demolition of Church Buildings, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Mistreatment of Soldiers in the Army, 1974 -1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Discrimination in Employment, 1977-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Discrimination in Education, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Misuse of Psychiatry, 1971-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. Attacks in the Media (1 of 2), 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Church. Attacks in the Media (2 of 2), 1971-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. House searches. Confiscation of Literature and Property, 1977-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Oppressive Practices against Unregistered Baptist Believers. Deprivation of Parental Rights, 1970-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Life. General, 1973-1979, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Life. Services and Rituals, 1968, 1977-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Life. Preaching, Evangelism, and Conversions, 1971-1988, 1988, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Life. Official Church Publications. Khristianin, no. 3 (March), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Clergy and Priesthood, 1978-1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. General, 1963, 1972-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Bondarenko, Iosif, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Khorev, Mikhail, 1971-1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Kriuchkov, Gennadii, 1971-1979, 1987, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Miniakov, Dmitrii, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Rumachik, Petr, 1975, 1980-1982, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (1 of 10), 1967-1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (2 of 10), 1975 January-May (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (3 of 10), 1975 June-December (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (4 of 10), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (5 of 10), 1976 January-August (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (6 of 10), 1976 September-December (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (7 of 10), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (8 of 10), 1979 January-May (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (9 of 10), 1979 June-December (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii (10 of 10), 1980-2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii. Articles and Plays, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii. Testimony to the Commission on Security and Co-operation in Europe (CSCE) (1 of 2), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Georgii. Testimony to the Commission on Security and Co-operation in Europe (CSCE) (2 of 2), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Clergy. Vins, Petr, 1969, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Unregistered Baptists Church. International Contacts. General (1 of 2), 1967-1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Unregistered Baptists Church. International Contacts. General (2 of 2), 1976-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. International Contacts. Western Reactions (1 of 2), 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. International Contacts. Western Reactions (2 of 2), 1976-1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Meetings. Prayer Groups, 1966-1979, 1983, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Protests, 1972-1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Council of Relatives of Evangelical Christian Baptist Prisoners, 1971-1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Conscientious Objection, 1977-1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds, 1973-1982, 1986-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Contacts with Foreigners, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Printing Press. Underground Publication. General, 1967-1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Unofficial Religious Education, 1966, 1970, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Underground Production of Literature, 1971-1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Theology. Education. Atheism, 1966-1980, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Schism., 1966-1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Statistics, 1967, 1972-1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Relations with Fellow Believers, 1970-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Ecumenical Relations with Other Denominations, 1968, 1977-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Involvement on Secular Affairs and Politics. Pronouncements on Secular Affairs, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Music and Literature. General, 1977, 1984, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Music and Literature. Bible, 1966-1985, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Women, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Children and Youth, 1966-1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Family, 1969, 1976-1981, 1985, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Family Problems, 1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Visual Materials (1 of 5), 1964-1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Visual Materials (2 of 5), 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Visual Materials (3 of 5), 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Visual Materials (4 of 5), 1978-1998 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Visual Materials (5 of 5), Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. Articles in Western Press. Atlantic Baptist, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Samizdat, 1961-1987, 2011, undated; 2
  The Unregistered Baptist Samizdat Subject Files contain materials pertaining to the persecution of Unregistered Baptist Church members fighting for their freedom of religion. The materials include unofficially circulated documents, reports, appeals, addresses, original and translated literary works, and underground religious literature which never passed through Soviet censorship and were not officially published. The series is in good condition.
  - Unregistered Baptist Church. History, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. General, 1969-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. General. Correspondence from Ukraine, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Dik, A. Ia., 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Khailo, V. (1 of 2), 1974-1977 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Khailo, V. (2 of 2), 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Kozlov, V. I., 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Moiseev, Ivan, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Sigarev, M.L., 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Skripnikova, A.M., 1962-1971 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Individual Unregistered Baptist Believers. Vins Family, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Canon Law, 1985 May (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (1 of 6), 1961-1966 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (2 of 6), 1962 March 22 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (3 of 6), 1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (4 of 6), 1975 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (5 of 6), 1965 April 14 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Unregistered Baptist Church Administration. Council of Churches of Evangelical Christians and Baptists (6 of 6), 1961-1966 (Box 10, Folder 18)